Guide to the Georg Kreisel Correspondence with Jean van Heijenoort
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Georg Kreisel correspondence with Jean van Heijenoort
1949-1981
SC0233
Kreisel, Georg, 1923-
6 Linear feet
Correspondence, notes, memoranda, articles and other materials by Professor Georg Kreisel, sent to his colleague, Professor J. van Heijenoort of Harvard University. Includes some correspondence with other colleagues.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of J. van Heijenoort, 1981.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence, notes, memoranda, articles and other materials by Professor Georg Kreisel, sent to his colleague, Professor J. van Heijenoort of Harvard University. Includes some correspondence with other colleagues.
Access Terms
Heijenoort, Jean van.; Kreisel, Georg, 1923-; Stanford University. Department of Philosophy. Faculty.; Logic, Symbolic and Mathematical.; Philosophy.
Collection Contents
- Correspondence, 1949-1981
  - Kreisel-Buffalo, Notions of Proof, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Foundations of Mathematics 1900-1950, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Interpretations of Analysis, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Review of Mostowski, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Two Expository Notes on Foundations, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Kreisel - Misc., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Kreisel - Predicative Analysis, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Kreisel - Misc. Letters, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Elementary Logic, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Kriesel, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Some Concepts concerning formal systems..., 1952 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Kreisel - Brussels Congress, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - A variant to Hilbert's Theory..., 1953 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - On a problem of Henkin's, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Remark on Complete Interpretations by Models, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Mathematical significance of Consistency Proofs, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Ordinal Logics and the Characterization of Informal Concepts of Proof, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Kreisel - Wittgenstein's Remarks on the Foundation of Mathematics, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Mathematical significance of Consistency Proofs, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Kreisel - Cantor- Bendixson Theorem, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - The axiom of choice and the class of Hyper-Arithmetic Functions, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Kreisel - Letter to Wang, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Kreisel - Letter to Parsons, 23410 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Kreisel- Review of Dreben, Andrews and Aanderaa, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Functions, ordinals, species, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Functions, ordinals, species, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Kreisel - Mathematical logic...[Russell volume], 1967 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Kreisel - Buffalo - Draft, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Lawless Sequences of Natural Numbers, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Functions, ordinals, species, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Kreisel - The Formalist - positivist doctrine of..., 1969 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Note on arithmetic models for consistent forumlae of the predicate calculus, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Kreisel - Set theoretic problems suggested by the notion of potential totality, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Kreisel - Intuitionistic mathematics, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Lectures, Course Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Kreisel - Lectures on proof theory, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Formal Rules and Questions of Justifying Mathematical Practice, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Kreisel, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Kreisel - Report on intuitionsim - Vol. 2, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Kreisel - Der unheilvolle Einbruch de Logik in die Mathematik, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Various Articles by Kreisel, circa 1969-1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Review of Brouwer's Collected Works I, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Kreisel - Hilbert's Problem, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Kreisel, Jeferman, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Notions of Proof, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Bertraud Russell's logic, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Kreisel - Oslo - Draft, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Axiomatizations of Nonstandard Analysis, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Kreisel - Buffalo, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Kreisel - Lecture Notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Some Concepts concerning formal systems of number theory, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Kreisel - Cours, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Kreisel- AAAS Meeting Papers, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Some purposes of generalizing recursion theory, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Der unheilvolle Einbruch de Logik in die Mathematik, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Review of Brouwer's Collected Works, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Elementary logic: Some..., 1976 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Predicative Analysis, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Kreisel, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Proposed Research, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Kreisel - Letters to Van Heijenoort, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Farikh, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1970-1975 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Generalized inductive definitions, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - La predicativite, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Lawless Sequences of Natural Numbers, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Only Recursive Problems are Positively Reducible, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Kreisel & Krivine - Corrections, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Kreisel & Wang, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Elementary completeness properties of intuitionistic logic, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Kreisel on Herbrand, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - On the interpretation of..., 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - On the concepts of completeness, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Niffo-American Conference, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - On the concepts of completeness, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Topics in Proof Theory, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Some conservative extensions of Primitive Recursive Arithmetic, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Review of Gentzen (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bibliography, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Report on intuitionism, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Kreisel, Mints, Simpson, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Formal Rules and Questions of Justifying Mathematical Practice, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Elements of proof theory, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Course on intuitionism, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Kreisel, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Kreisel - Misc. Correspondence, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Kreisel - Memoirs, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Countable Functions and Neighborhood Functions, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Kreisel Seminar Notes and Construction Proof Theory, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Kreisel - Proofs and Rules: Topics for illustrating Wittgenstein's style of thoughts, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Kreisel - The motto of "Investigations" and the philosophy of proofs and rules, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Memos and Papers, circa 1977 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Kreisel - Rapport Sur La These de Girard, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Kreisel - Finitely definable number theoretic functions..., 1972 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Review of Dreisel, Buffalo - Church's Thesis, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Kreisel - Facts and Fantasies about logic in philosophy, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Kreisel - Some reasons for Generalizing Recursion Theory, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Report on intuitionism - Stanford, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - J. Van Heijenoort - Constructionist Approch to Logic, 1979 Jun 25 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Seminar 1978, Definitions and Preface (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Memos and Letters, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - "On the Kind of Date Needed for a Theory of Proofs", 1976 Nov 4 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Kreisel, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Kreisel, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Kreisel, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Kreisel, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Kreisel Proofs of Rules, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Memos and Letters, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Kreisel Letter to Lopez-Escobar, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Kreisel Some uses of Mathmatics, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Kreisel Two Notes, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Kreisel A Survey of Proof Theories, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Review of..., Undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Kreisel, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Kreisel- Foundations of Mathmatics:1900-1950, Undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Axiomatizations of nonstandard analysis, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Letter to Heyting, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Observations of a recent, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Wie die Beweistheorie, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Kreisel Introduction, 1978 Oct 11 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Kreisel Letters, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Class notes, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - GK Closed, Undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Mints Correspondence, 1970 Oct (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Dreben Crrespondence with Kresiel, 1968 Oct 9 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence Confidential Letters, 1969-1977 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Kreisel, 1974-1979 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - On "Kurt Godel" and a Paper by G. Patzig, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Aussagenquantoren, 1980 May 27 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Five Notes on the Application of Proof Theory to Computer Science, 1971 Dec 1 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Kreisel, Lacombe, and Sheonfield, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Kresisel and Levy, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Kreisel, Sheonfield, and Wang, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Kreisel and Sacks Metarecursive, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Kreisel and Cakeuti, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Howard and Kreisel, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Sherman and Kreisel - Persisitant and invariant formulas, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Kreisel Wohlordrungen, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Letters to Van Heijemoort, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - GK Letter to van Heijemoort, 1981 May 21 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - GK Letter to van Heijemoort, 1983 Apr 14 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - GK Letter to Codd, 1983, Apri 12 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - GK Letter to Fefermann, 1983 Apr 11 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - GK Review of van der Hoeven, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - GK Some comments on Persons, 1983 Apr 13 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Course Notes, 1969 Autumn (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - GK Letter to van Heijemoort, 1983 Apr 13 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - GK Letter to Lost, 1983 Apr 8 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - GK Letter to van Heijemoort, 1983 Apr 11 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - GK Letter to van Heijemoort, 1983 Apr 4 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Unidentified, 1970 May (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Kreisal Kurt Godel, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Kresiel Article on Brouwer, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Seminar Spring, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Letters to JvH, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1982 Nov 1 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Letter to Van Heijenoort, 1982 Nov 11 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1982 Dec 8 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1982 Nov 29 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Postscript, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Errata, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Abstract structures, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Category theory, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Letters to JvH, 1981 Mar 16, 17 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Frege's Foundation Auct, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Letter to Poffer, 1983 Apr 18 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Letter to van heijenoort, 1983 Apr 18 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Kreisel, G, 1983 Mar 15 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Kreisel, G, 1983 Feb 15 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Kresiel, G, 1983, Mar 14 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - GK, Undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Kreisel, Frege's Foundation, 1983 Jan 9 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Kreisel Ltter to Croelstra, 1983 Mar 18 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Kreisel Dur Bewertung, Undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Kreisel, circa 1983 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Kreisel Corrections ott eh Godel memoir, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Kreisel Letter to JvH, 1983 Jan 21 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Kreisel What is to be done?, 1983 Feb 22 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Kreisel Appendix, 1983 Feb 21 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - GK, 1983 Jan 25 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Letters, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Letters, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Letter to Sundholm, 1982 Jan 6 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Theorums, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Kreisel Review of Lauben and Kennedy, Undated (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Four lectures on proof theory, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Some uses of proof theory, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Metamathematic mit beschrankten uitteln, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Was hat die Logik, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Kreisel, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Letters to JvH, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Kreisel Constructive lgoic versus algebratization, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Report, Undated (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Review of Beeson, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Whittgenstein Lecture, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Appendi to teh Brouwer Article, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - On a simple-minded question, undated (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Letter to Wagner, 1981 Dec 16 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - Report on Sundholm, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Errata, undated (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Letter to Cakeuti, 1981 Dec 7 (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - Kreisel Thinking About, 1984 Mar 19 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Kreisel Review of Teferman, 1984 Mar 19 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Godel's Ambivalence, 1983 May (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Kreisel's Corrections to Frege's Foundations, 1983 May (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Kreisel Was hat die Grundlagenforschung, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Kreisel aud Macintyre, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Was hat die Wissenchaft, 1982 Nov 1 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Ernige Erlauterungeu, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Kreisel Letter to Feferman, 1982 Dec 12 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Notizen, 1983 Oct 12 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Notizen, 1983 Oct 11 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Logische uud, 1983 Dec 2 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Godel's Ambivalence, 1983 Jul 16 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Aus der Crickkiste0, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Was hat die, 1983 Oct (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Letter to Chaussky-Todd, 1983 Sep 5 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Research proposal, 1983 Oct 1983 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Kreisel Progress report, 1983 Oct 19 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Kreisel Godels Ambivalence, undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Review of Kripke, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Kreisel Miscellaneous, 1983 Sept 23 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Kreisel Miscellaneous, 1982 Nov (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Review of Russian book containing some of his papers, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Kreisel Letter to Burge, 1984 Jan (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Letter to Judith Miller, 1984 Jan 5 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Letter to Oxford registrar, 1984 Jan (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Dubious assumptions, 1984 Mar 9 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Self-review, 1984 Mar 7 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Comments on non-montonic logic, 1984 Mar 8 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Letter to Olga Caussky Todd, 1984 Feb 27 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1984 Feb 23 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1984 Feb 23 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Letter to Gabriel Dirac, 1984 Jan 29 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Letter to Pour, 1984 Feb 2 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Lecture Notes, 1984 Jan 27 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Swan Song, 1984 Jan 26 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Note to van Heijenoort, 1984 Jan 17 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Seminar on..., 1984 Jan (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Twentieth century, 1984 Jan 21 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1982 Sep 20 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1982 Sep 15 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1982 Sep 15 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1982 Oct 5 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1982 Oct 4 (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1982 Sep 23 (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1982 Oct 18 (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Sep 23 (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Sep 30 (Box 12, Folder 48)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Oct 17 (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Oct 31 (Box 12, Folder 50)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Nov 2 (Box 12, Folder 51)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Nov 4 (Box 12, Folder 52)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Nov 7 (Box 12, Folder 53)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Nov 14 (Box 12, Folder 54)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Nov 21 (Box 12, Folder 55)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Nov 28 (Box 12, Folder 56)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Dec 2 (Box 12, Folder 57)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1982 Apr 23 (Box 12, Folder 58)
  - Letter to JvH, 1983 Apr 27 (Box 12, Folder 59)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Apr 29 (Box 12, Folder 60)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 May 10 (Box 12, Folder 61)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 May 26 (Box 12, Folder 62)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 May 31 (Box 12, Folder 63)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Jun 3 (Box 12, Folder 64)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Jun 10 (Box 12, Folder 65)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Jun 17 (Box 12, Folder 66)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Jun 15 (Box 12, Folder 67)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Jul 1 (Box 12, Folder 68)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Jul 4 (Box 12, Folder 69)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Jul 12 (Box 12, Folder 70)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Jul 18 (Box 12, Folder 71)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Jul 29 (Box 12, Folder 72)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Jul 27 (Box 12, Folder 73)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Jul 25 (Box 12, Folder 74)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Aug 8 (Box 12, Folder 75)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Aug 11 (Box 12, Folder 76)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Aug 23 (Box 12, Folder 77)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Aug 30 (Box 12, Folder 78)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Sep 2 (Box 12, Folder 79)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1983 Sep 16 (Box 12, Folder 80)
  - Report, 1984 Mar 9 (Box 12, Folder 81)
  - Letter to van Heijenoort, 1984 Mar 20 (Box 12, Folder 82)
  - Report on Curchin, 1984 Feb 17 (Box 12, Folder 83)